Sue Darby

Seeking new opportunities! Business Analysis/Technical Writing/SoftwareSupport

sue.a.darby@gmail.com

Summary

Sue is open to new opportunities in the Anchorage, Alaska area or remote/telecommute from anywhere else.

I am seeking full time work and have over 20 years of experience as an advanced computer user and writer. I have been proven to be detail oriented in determining the requirements for both users and technical staff providing a unique bridge between management and technical staff. Creative in the use of technology to solve problems and create detailed business processes.

Experience

Business Consultant at Alaska Office Specialists

October 2008 - Present

Alaska Office Specialists started as a virtual assistant service and has morphed into a website management service for craft businesses. Sue Darby who owns and operates the business uses her unique skill set to build and manage websites for other businesses who sell or make crafts. This can include hosting sites or updating already built sites. It is her experience with her own craft businesses that gives her the insight necessary to keep a crafting business site running.

Key Contributions

- WordPress management, installation, updates and security of 10+ sites
- HTML editing and scratch coding including using Bootstrap Framework or other systems
- CSS editing and scratch coding using various frameworks
- JavaScript including node.js and angular
- FTP management of websites
- Social Media management including Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn both manually and with Hootsuite
- Manage content on cloud based services such as DropBox, Google Drive, Toodledo and others

Owner, Designer, Web Master at Sue's Tiny Costumes

September 1995 - Present

Sue's Tiny Costumes makes patterns in the micro scale from 1/2" tall baby dolls to 18" lady doll patterns. Sue Darby owns and operates the business and has since 1996. She has published 2 books to the Library of Congress "Pattern Drafting for Miniatures" and "Pattern Making for Dolls". In addition to these books she has self-published over 100 patterns for dolls and been featured multiple times in doll and miniature magazines. Each pattern takes many hours of planning and work from design concept, to measuring and

drafting the pattern for the doll both by hand and by computer, to testing the pattern and writing the technical instructions for others to complete the same design. Beyond these basics for each pattern are diagrams of sewing techniques and photography of the finished items for both the pattern and for her website, social media channels and other marketing material.

Key Contributions

- Project planning of technical books and patterns
- Project management of pattern drafting projects
- Published author of 2 books and over 100 sewing patterns
- Photography of finished items for patterns and website
- Website design, development and management including new content and security

Awards & Publications

- International Doll Magazine, Pattern Consultant 6 published patterns 2004-2005
- Dolls In Miniature- article 2005
- Doll Castle News- article 2005
- State Fair 2005 Little Bo Peep and her Sheep (Kitty Collier & Tiny Betsy)

Senior Services Technician

February 2014 - Present

Sue Darby performs a variety of support and technical functions in the administration of the Provider Certification & Compliance Unit for the Medicaid Home and Community Based Waiver and Personal Care Assistance program. This position provides support and assistance to program managers and is responsible for program specific work of a senior service oriented agency, develops and maintains systems to track certification information and prepares reports for professional staff which are used internally and externally. The position serves a key role in the Provider Certification Unit as related to regulatory compliance, client health and safety, and continuous quality improvement.

Key Contributions

Certification

- Process 1500+ incoming applications, distribute to reviewers and issue reminder letters to providers who are untimely
- Sort and filter 500+ emails monthly ensuring each is categorized correctly for processing by myself or team members
- Process over 5,000 files for archives or off site storage equaling over 160 cubic feet of paper
- Master user for MS Office 2003-2013 including testing of newer computer builds for IT as super user Compliance
- Participates in planning and developing system work orders to improve systems support for the unit.
- Build Master Site Review Tool improving data collection and notification efficiency by 85%
- Maintain calendar and email management for team tracking during travel
- "Other Duties as Assigned"
- Builds & maintains UMLs of unit processes, writes or updates written processes as assigned

- Unit SharePoint Administrator and Manager building tools to track processes that internal DS3 database does not currently
- SME called on to define unit needs for reporting in new database system during development stages
- Participated in user testing of database in development following scripts and offering feedback on usability and functionality

Promotion in 2014

Webmistress

October 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Recruited to work on iA3's website during the start up phase for website management and content development

Key Contributions

- Setup and configuration of theme, home page, privacy policy and additional content
- Facebook and Twitter account management
- Gaining technical knowledge and expertise regarding the hardware and software of the iA3 EdgeBrain a micro PC controlling industrial level water systems

Office Assistant II at State of Alaska

May 2008 - February 2014 (5 years 9 months)

Transitioned to the Senior Services Technician in 2014 as the work as an Office Assistant II became more complex than the position allows.

Administrative support for 10-15 professionals providing tasks such as mail outs, mail merges, email management and filing support. Also provided team leadership to Department of Vocational Rehabilitation and Mature Alaskans Seeking Skills Training participants teaching a variety of clerical and computer skills and offering assistance as necessary. Progressed from a level I to a level II Office Assistant within about a year of starting with the State of Alaska. Quickly became a sought out subject matter expert in Excel, archiving, SharePoint and certification application processing.

Key Contributions

- Responds to and takes appropriate action when within prescribed parameters, redirects to the correct professional staff when beyond knowledge base or those parameters, routes various emails to specific professional staff for decisions and action.
- Monitors Provider Certification email inbox which is the publicly posted email and web portal for all providers and applicants.
- Serves as subject matter expert on records retention procedures and archiving/off-site storage processes and advises professional staff on these procedures.
- Database management, maintains systems to ensure data integrity.
- Serves as lead in selecting, training and oversight of DVR, MAAST and administrative support
- Provides support and maintenance of the unit's copiers, fax machines and other machinery in the office.
- Prepares materials for dissemination to providers, including recertification notifications
- Keeps Provider Certification records and files organized and complete.

- Provides records copies for various records requests for criminal cases, public requests, etc. Ensure complete records are provided.
- Provides detailed information on program regulations; advises the public on program applicability and requirements

Career Development Mentor & Computer Instructor at Nine Star Education & Employment Services April 2006 - April 2008 (2 years)

Sue Darby, was an AmeriCorps Member, in the Career Development Center of Nine Star Education and Employment Services. Sue brought to the Career Development Center a variety of skills gained as an owner of a small business, including a high level of personalized customer service, and the ability to teach life skills, as well as computer skills, to a diverse group of customers.

Administrative

- Cut Management Information Systems input time by 50%
- Create templates used for generating reports
- Input clients into File Maker Pro via Citrix
- Brainstorm ways to streamline the administrative processes
- Answer phones & questions from the public

Computer Instruction

- Develop class curriculum
- Teach computer classes
- Aid students in preparation for the MOS exams
- Answer student questions about various software

Career Development Mentor

- Teaches goal setting workshops
- Confers with clients to determine what program will be most helpful
- Assesses clients for barriers and brainstorm ways to overcome them
- Drafts and edits resumes, cover letters and other business correspondence
- Directs clients to appropriate resources and assists clients in their use of outside assistance
- Assists clients in registration for and use of the ALEXSYS system for the Department of Labor
- Conducts job-matching to find good fit between clients and hiring companies

Education

Charter College

Bachelors/Associates, Business Management Practice & Office Applications, 2006 - 2009

Activities and Societies: Dean's List, Alpha Beta Kappa, Alpha Gamma Sigma

OSTraining & Udemy

Technolgy, Tech, Personal & Professional Development, 2016

Free Code Camp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering, 2016 - 2017

Solano Community College

Certificate, Fashion Design, 1995 - 1997

Activities and Societies: n/a

GNC Web Creations Online Search Engine Optimization Class

none, SEO, 2002 - 2020

Activities and Societies: Actively participate in online forum and group discussions on business and building

websites.

Fairfield High

Diploma, 1992 - 1994

Activities and Societies: Scarlet Brigade Marching Band Future Farmers of America

Honors and Awards

Alpha Beta Kappa Honors Society, Charter College, Anchorage, AK, Dean's List, Charter College, Anchorage, AK, Microsoft Office 2003 Master, Nine Star Education & Employment Services, Anchorage, AKAbout Sue: http://www.sue-a-darby.com/about.html

Technical Writing, Web Master, Marketing, Business Owner, Photography, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Perl, VisualBasic, Product Design & Development, Document Design, & Formatting, Streamline Administrative Processes, Database Improvements, Data Tracking, Report Processes, Project Management, Task Management, Goals, Budgets, Timelines, GANTT Charts, Master Certified MS Office 2003, MS Office 95-2010, MS Project, MS Visio, MS SharePoint 2007-2010, OneNote, AdobePro X & XI, Adobe DC, Corel Draw Suite, UML. Visio,

Sue Darby

Seeking new opportunities! Business Analysis/Technical Writing/SoftwareSupport

sue.a.darby@gmail.com



Contact Sue on LinkedIn